Astronauts are seeing weird things in
space. So during Apollo 11, astronaut
Neil Armstrong said that he saw strange
flashes of blue light even when his eyes
were closed. So we know that once they
leave the protective shield of Earth's
atmosphere and our magnetic field,
astronauts are exposed to all kinds of
new threats, most of which you can't see
with the human eye, like trillions of
these high energy particles moving at
nearly the speed of light. Most pass
right through the astronauts. Sometimes
they hit right in the astronaut's eye
and they move through the eye water
faster than the speed of light in water,
which creates this special reaction
that's kind of like a sonic boom, but
instead of the boom sound, it erupts as
this incredibly fast flash of blue light
directly in the eye of the astronaut,
visible even with their eyes closed. But
we have a lot of questions about where
these particles actually come from. So,
we've built these huge machines to catch
them. to see those subscribe.